like hospital-acquired infections. I believe this has got to be, in part, a building ecology problem. All right, I'm going to tell you one more story about this building. I am collaborating with Charlie Brown. He's an architect, and Charlie is deeply concerned about global climate change. He's dedicated his life to sustainable design. When he met me and realized that it was possible for him to study in a quantitative way how his design choices impacted the ecology and biology of this building, he got really excited, because it added a new dimension to what he did. He went from thinking just about energy to also starting to think about human health. He helped design some of the air handling systems in this building and the way it was ventilated. So what I'm first going to show you is air that we sampled outside of the building. What you're looking at is a signature of bacterial communities in the outdoor air, and how they vary over time. Next I'm going to show you what happened when we experimentally manipulated classrooms. We blocked them off at night so that they got no ventilation. A lot of buildings are operated this way, probably where you work, and companies do this to save money on their energy bill. What we found is that these rooms remained relatively stagnant until Saturday, when we opened the vents up again. When you walked into those rooms, they smelled really bad, and our data suggests that it had something to do with leaving behind the airborne bacterial soup from people the day before. Contrast this to rooms that were designed using a sustainable passive design strategy where air came in from the outside through louvers. In these rooms, the air tracked the outdoor air relatively well, and when Charlie saw this, he got really excited. He felt like he had made a good choice with the design process because it was both energy efficient and it washed away the building's resident microbial landscape. The examples that I just gave you are about architecture, but they're relevant to the design of anything. Imagine designing with the kinds of microbes that we want in a plane or on a phone. There's a new microbe, I just discovered it. It's called BLIS, and it's been shown to both ward off pathogens and give you good breath. Wouldn't it be awesome if we all had BLIS on our phones? A conscious approach to design, I'm calling it bioinformed design, and I think it's possible. Thank you. (Applause)
como infecciones intrahospitalarias. Creo que esto se debe, en parte, a un problema de construcción ecológica. Bueno, les voy a contar una historia más sobre este edificio. Estoy colaborando con Charlie Brown. Es arquitecto, y Charlie está muy preocupado por el cambio climático global. Ha dedicado su vida al diseño sostenible. Cuando me conoció y se dio cuenta de que podía estudiar de forma cuantitativa cómo sus decisiones de diseño afectaban a la ecología y biología de este edificio, se entusiasmó mucho, porque aportaba una nueva dimensión a su trabajo. Pasó de pensar solo en la energía a empezar a pensar también en la salud. Ayudó a diseñar algunas de las unidades de tratamiento del aire en este edificio, y la forma en la que se ventila. Así que lo primero que les voy a enseñar son las muestras de aire que tomamos en el exterior del edificio. Lo que están viendo es la marca de las comunidades bacterianas en el aire exterior, y cómo varían con el tiempo. Lo siguiente que les voy a enseñar es lo que pasó cuando manipulamos experimentalmente las aulas. Las cerramos por la noche de forma que no tuvieran ventilación Muchos edificios funcionan así, probablemente en su lugar de trabajo, y las empresas lo hacen para ahorrar costes en la factura de energía. Lo que descubrimos fue que estas aulas se mantenían relativamente estancadas hasta el sábado, cuando volvimos a abrir los respiraderos. Cuando entrábamos a esas aulas, olían fatal, y nuestros datos apuntan a que tenía que ver con la sopa de bacterias transmitidas por aire de la gente del día anterior. Comparémoslo con las habitaciones que se crearon con una estrategia de diseño pasivo donde el aire entraba desde el exterior por las persianas. En estas habitaciones, el aire seguía el rastro del aire exterior relativamente bien, y cuando Charlie vio esto, se emocionó mucho. Tenía la sensación de haber tomado una buena decisión en el proceso del diseño, porque tanto era eficiente en el uso de energía como era limpio el paisaje de microbios residentes del edificio. Los ejemplos que les acabo de dar son sobre arquitectura, pero son relevantes al diseñar cualquier cosa. Imaginen diseñar con los tipos de microbios que queramos en un avión o en un teléfono. Hay un nuevo microbio, lo acabo de descubrir. Se llama BLIS, y se ha demostrado que rechaza agentes patógenos y proporciona buen aliento. ¿No sería fantástico que todos tuviéramos BLIS en nuestros teléfonos? Un enfoque de diseño con conciencia, que voy a llamar diseño bioinformado, y creo que es posible. Gracias. (Aplausos)